whitenyourwhites.com 2010-06-30

# Clorox Privacy Policy For United States Consumers

Clorox Privacy Policy For United States Consumers  
Our Privacy Policy for Canadian sites may be found here.

**Last Revised: October 1, 2007**

The Clorox Company and its affiliates and subsidiaries (collectively, "Clorox") are committed to the protection and appropriate use of the information you submit to us online. This Privacy Policy (the "Policy") describes how we collect, use and safeguard personal information obtained from individual consumers in the United States through this website (the "Site").

What Personal Information Do We Collect?  
Clorox collects personal information from visitors to this Site such as names, postal addresses, e-mail addresses, user ID, password and, if you make an online purchase, credit card information. 

Personal information is collected only for specific purposes and with the knowledge of the person providing the personal information. To access the Site you are not required to register or submit any personal information. 

The content of this Site is not directed to children and Clorox does not knowingly collect personal information from persons under eighteen years of age. 

Why Do We Collect This Personal Information?  
Purposes for which Clorox may collect personal information online include, but are not limited to: 

Sweepstakes and Contest Entries. From time to time, Clorox offers sweepstakes, contests and other promotions (each, a "Promotion") that require online registration. Persons wishing to participate in those Promotions are asked to provide some personal information. Some of the information requested for this purpose is optional, but other requested information, such as the individual's name and e-mail address, is mandatory because it will be needed to identify and notify winners. Also, some Promotions may require selection of a user ID and password by the individual. You should carefully review the rules, if any, of each Promotion in which you participate through the Site, as they may contain additional important information about Clorox's use of your personal information. To the extent that the terms and conditions of such rules concerning the treatment of your personal information conflict with this Policy, the terms and conditions of such rules shall control. 

Coupon and Rebate Requests. Visitors to the Site may be offered the opportunity to apply for rebates or request discount coupons associated with Clorox products. Those visitors may be asked to provide certain personal information such as names, postal addresses and e-mail addresses in connection with those offers. 

"Contact Us" and "Write to Us" Features. Clorox encourages visitors to the Site to contact us with questions and requests. Clorox also offers e-mail news updates for visitors who expressly request that service. Personal information of persons using these features may be collected in order to facilitate our responses to those inquiries. 

Product Registration. Purchasers of certain Clorox products may want to register their purchases online so that they can take advantage of warranties, product updates and other benefits. Purchasers are asked to submit certain personal information such as names, postal addresses and e-mail addresses as part of the product registration process. 

Loyalty Program Registration. Clorox offers various "loyalty" programs that provide benefits to purchasers of Clorox products. The loyalty program online registration process requests personal information concerning the individual who signs up. Participants in loyalty programs also may need to provide personal information in order to redeem program benefits. 

Requests for Consumer Brochures and Videos. Clorox may offer product information, including brochures and videos, through the Site. Persons ordering those materials are asked to provide their name and postal address. 

What Other Information Do We Collect?  
We collect non-personally identifiable information, which does not personally identify you, in the following ways: 

**Consumer Surveys.** Clorox sometimes conducts online consumer surveys or asks for information from persons completing online forms. This information, such as household size, past purchases and household income, is provided voluntarily and is never required for participation in a sweepstakes, contest or loyalty program, to register a product or to obtain product information. When such information is not combined with any personal information, such information is considered to be non-personally identifiable information, as it does not personally identify you or any other user. 

**Aggregated Information.** Additionally, we may aggregate personal information in a manner such that the information does not personally identify you or any other user of the Site, for example, by using personal information to calculate the percentage of our users who have a particular telephone area code. Such aggregate information is considered non-personally identifiable information for purposes of this Policy. 

**"Clickstream" Data.** The Site automatically collects certain data concerning its interactions with visitors that facilitate Site operation, management and planning. Such data may include the IP address of your computer, the date and time of an online request, the type of browser and operating system used by your computer, the time required to download information you requested, and error codes generated while your browser is in contact with the Site. 

**Cookies and Other Technologies.** Cookies are small text files, placed on the hard drive of a visitor's computer, that facilitate the operation of the Site and visitors' use of the Site. As is standard practice on many corporate websites, the Site uses cookies and other technologies, such as pixel tags and web beacons, to help us understand which websites our visitors are coming from and what websites they go to when they leave our Site, which parts of the Site are the most popular, and how much time they spend on our Site. We also use cookies and other technologies to facilitate participation in our loyalty programs, as well as to customize your experience and provide greater convenience each time you interact with us.   
You can configure your browser to accept all cookies, reject all cookies, or notify you when a cookie is set. (Each browser is different, so click the "Help" menu of your browser to learn how to change your cookie preferences.) If you reject all cookies, you will not be able to use those services on the Site that require you to sign in.   
Some uses of cookies in connection with the Site may be under the control of third-party entities that Clorox retains for the management of certain programs and fulfillment of specific visitor/consumer requests. Clorox requests these entities to confine their use of cookies and similar technologies, but Clorox cannot be responsible for third party uses of cookies. 

How Do We Use the Personal Information We Collect?  
Personal information provided by consumers and visitors to our Site is used to fulfill requests and transactions submitted through the Site. For example, if you choose to purchase a product or service through the Site, we may use your personal information to process your transaction and fulfill your order. If you contact us through the Site, we will use your personal information to respond to your queries and requests. If you register a product through the Site, we will use your personal information to fulfill your registration, and if you sign up for a loyalty program, we will use your personal information to administer the program. 

From time to time, in our sole discretion, we may use your personal information to send to you important information regarding the Site, or changes to our terms, conditions, and policies. Because this information may be important to your use of the Site, you may not opt- out of receiving such communications. 

If you choose to opt- in, we may use your personal information to send you marketing-related e-mails from us or from the particular brands to which you opted- in. If you change your mind, and would prefer not to receive such marketing-related e-mails, please review the "Opt-In Policy" section below. 

We may also use your personal information for our internal business purposes, such as for data analysis, for audits, to improve our website, to analyze usage patterns and to improve our services. 

When Do We Disclose the Personal Information We Collect?  
We may provide your personal information to our third party service providers to fulfill requests and transactions submitted through the Site. For example, Clorox may use third party service providers to conduct consumer surveys, and Clorox sometimes shares information submitted in connection with sweepstakes, contests, loyalty programs and other programs with vendors that Clorox has retained to administer those and other programs. Clorox may also share certain information with third party organizations for the purpose of processing your credit card transactions. Clorox seeks to restrict third parties' use of such data to the purposes for which it has been provided and to ensure the third parties do not disclose that information to unauthorized parties. 

If you choose to opt- in, Clorox may from time to time share your personal information with our affiliates, or with our business and promotional partners that offer products or services that we believe will be of interest to you. If you change your mind, and would prefer that we not share your personal information with our affiliates or with our business and promotional partners for their marketing purposes, please review the "Opt-In Policy" section below. 

Clorox will provide personal information to law enforcement authorities and other entities where Clorox determines that such disclosure is required by subpoena, warrant, court order or other applicable law or process. Additionally, Clorox may disclose personal information if we determine that such disclosure is required to enforce our Terms of Use; to protect our operations; to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of Clorox, you or others; and to permit us to pursue available remedies or limit the damages that we may sustain. 

Although Clorox seeks to require companies with which it does business, and to which personal information is provided, to protect such personal information, Clorox cannot be responsible for third parties' violations of this Policy or of any other rights of visitors or consumers that use this Site. 

Clorox may transfer personal information and other information, collected online from visitors and consumers, to a purchaser or successor entity in connection with the sale of Clorox, a subsidiary or affiliate or line of business associated with Clorox, or substantially all of the assets of Clorox or one of its subsidiaries, affiliates or lines of business. 

How Do We Use the Non-Personally Identifiable Information We Collect?  
Because non-personally identifiable information does not personally identify you, we may use such information for any purpose. In addition, we reserve the right to share such non-personally identifiable information, which does not personally identify you, with third parties, for any purpose. For example, we may share non-personally identifiable information collected in connection with consumer surveys and other activities, with consumer research and marketing firms. 

In some instances, we may combine non-personally identifiable information with personal information (such as embedding e-mail addresses in cookies or where specific programs associated with this Site require a user ID and password, and you have the option of requesting that we save your user ID and password so that you will not have to reenter that information the next time you access the Site — this function is accomplished by placement of a cookie). If we do combine any non-personally identifiable information with personal information, the combined information will be treated by us as personal information hereunder as long as it is so combined. 

Third Party Links  
The Site may contain links to third party web sites. These linked sites are not under Clorox's control and we are not responsible for the privacy practices or the contents of any such linked site, or any link contained in any linked site. We provide such links only as a convenience, and the inclusion of a link on the Site does not imply endorsement of the linked site by Clorox. If you provide any personal information through any such third party web site, your transaction will occur on such third party's web site (not the Site) and the personal information you provide will be collected by, and controlled by the privacy policy of, that third party. We recommend that you familiarize yourself with the privacy policies and practices of any such third parties. PLEASE NOTE THAT THIS POLICY DOES NOT ADDRESS THE PRIVACY OR INFORMATION PRACTICES OF ANY THIRD PARTIES.

Security  
Clorox takes measures designed to prevent unauthorized intrusion to the Site and the alteration, acquisition or misuse of personal information. Clorox cautions consumers and visitors to this Site, however, that no network is entirely secure. Accordingly, Clorox cannot be responsible for loss, corruption or unauthorized acquisition of personal information furnished to this Site and/or stored by us, or for any damages resulting from such loss, corruption or unauthorized acquisition.

Opt-In Policy  
If you change your mind, and do not wish to receive further marketing-related e-mails from us, or if you would prefer that we do not share your personal information (on a going-forward basis) with our affiliates and/or with our business and promotional partners for such affiliates' and/or business and promotional partners' marketing purposes, you may opt- out of receiving such marketing-related e-mails or from such sharing by logging in to your preference center or by clicking here. Please note that you may be given a choice as to whether you wish to cease receiving marketing messages from a particular brand as well as from Clorox generally. If you decide to opt out of receiving all marketing-related e-mails from Clorox, we will also cease sharing your personal information for direct marketing purposes on a going-forward basis with our affiliates and with our business and promotional partners. 

We will endeavor to comply with your request as soon as reasonably practicable. Please note that if you opt- out as described above, we will not be able to remove your personal information from the databases of affiliates or business and promotional partners with which we have already shared your personal information (i.e., to which we have already provided your personal information as of the date that we implement your opt-out request). If you wish to cease receiving marketing-related e-mails from such affiliates or business and promotional partners on a going-forward basis, please contact such affiliates or business and promotional partners directly or utilize any opt-out mechanisms set forth in their respective privacy policies or marketing-related e-mails. 

Changing or Removing Your Personal Information  
If you would like to review, correct, update or remove personal information that you have previously provided to us through the Site, you may do so by logging in to your preference center and making changes. 

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record-keeping purposes, and there may also be residual information that will remain within our databases and other records, which will not be removed therefrom. We are not responsible for removing information from the databases of third parties with whom we have already shared your personal information. 

Offline v. Online Practices  
This Policy applies solely to Clorox's online information-gathering and dissemination practices in connection with the Site, and does not apply to any of our practices conducted offline, with the following exception. Clorox may merge information collected about you through offline means with information that is stored in our databases along with information gathered online. Any such merged information, however, will not be disclosed to others except as permitted by this Policy.

Changes to Privacy Policy  
We encourage you to read this Policy before using the Site, and not to use the Site if you disagree with any part of this Policy. Your use of the Site signifies your agreement to all terms of this Policy. 

Please note that Clorox may revise this Policy from time to time. You should bookmark and periodically review this page to ensure that you are familiar with the most current version of this Policy. You can determine when this Policy was last revised by checking the "Last Revised" legend at the top of the Policy. Use of the Site following such changes constitutes your acceptance of the revised Policy then in effect. 

This Policy is the sole authorized statement of Clorox's practices concerning the collection, use and protection of personal information through this Site. Any summaries of this Policy generated by third party software or otherwise (for example, in connection with the "Platform for Privacy Preferences" or "P3P") shall have no legal effect, are in no way binding upon Clorox, and neither supersede nor modify this Policy. 

Questions?  
Questions regarding this Policy should be directed to the Clorox Security Office/Privacy at privacy@clorox.com, or at the following physical mailing address: The Clorox Company, Mail Stop 2334, 1221 Broadway, Oakland, California 94612-1888.  

Please note that this Policy applies to our Sites hosted in the United States. Our Privacy Policy for Canadian sites may be found here.
